我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother killed
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
by something impossible.
快跑  巴里
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
-妈妈  -让我父亲沉冤得雪
Mom! And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
如果你有需要
If you ever need anything,
我会以迅雷不及掩耳之势赶来
I will race over in a heartbeat.
我也一样  尽我最快的速度跑来
Same. Well, as fast as I can run.
尖端科技作战系统  原子侠
Advanced Technology Operating Mechanism--A.T.O.M.
你要用它来干什么
What are you gonna use it for?
保护这座城市的人
To protect the people of this city.
你认为威尔斯博士杀了巴里的妈妈吗
You think Dr. Wells killed Barry's mom?
还不知道原因
I don't know yet.
但我知道威尔斯的确藏有秘密
But I do know that Wells keeps secrets.
他描述奔跑的方式
The way that he described running--
感受风感受力量
feeling the wind and the power--
就像他在描述他的亲身体会
it's like he was talking from experience.
哈里森·威尔斯就是逆闪
Harrison Wells is The Reverse-Flash.
艾迪  我们需要你帮忙
Eddie, we need your help.
油门踩到底
Pedal to the metal.
有犯罪正在进行
We've got a 10-31 in progress.
十八街和橄榄街交汇处  闪光钻石珠宝店
Shiny Diamond, 18th and Olive.
离这里只有几个街区远
That's only a few blocks from here.
难道中城的混混都疯了吗
Has every crook in Central City gone crazy?
这是今晚第三起蓄意抢劫了
This is the third attempted robbery tonight.
巴里  又有一起了
Barry. We got another one.
你好
Hello.
十八街和橄榄街交汇处
18th and Olive.
知道了
Got it.
这是谁
Who's this?
公开露阴  鲍威尔公园
Oh. Indecent exposure. Powell Park.
那玩意你不应该随便拿出来给别人看
That ain't something you should be showing people.
他们要跑了  伙计们
They're getting away, guys.
他们跑不掉的  艾迪
They're not getting away, Eddie.
咱们先把前边这俩抓起来
Let's get these bozos up ahead of us first,
然后再去找闪光钻石珠宝店里的那些笨蛋
and then we'll worry about the idiots at the Shiny Diamond.
好的
All right.
不过  我们车上快没位置了
We're gonna run out of room, though.
我来搞定
I'll take care of that.
你觉得他那是什么意思
What do you think he meant by that?
原来是这意思
Oh. That's what he meant.
我觉得咱们甩掉他们了
I think we lost them.
不  你们没有
Oh, no, you didn't.
还有  你被捕了
And by the way, you're under arrest.
咱们得走了  马上  快点
We need to go. Now. Come on!
别动
Uh-uh. Freeze.
你们有东西丢了吗
You guys missing these?
趴在地上  趴在地上
On the ground. On the ground.
我只是好奇  不过...
So, uh, I'm just curious, but...
你们是没听说过我吗  还是怎样
have you guys not heard of me, or what?
干得好  警探
Nice work, detective.
-晚安  康博士  -晚安
- Good night, Dr. Kang. - Good night.
应用物理与自动机学
闪电侠
第一季  第十八集
受害者名叫林赛·康
Victim's name is Lindsay Kang,
哈德逊大学工程教授
engineering professor at Hudson University.
刚被授予终身教席
Just got tenure.
她的全身都覆盖着这些穿刺伤口
So, her whole body's covered in these puncture wounds
如同她脸上这些
you see on her face.
也许是咬痕
Bite marks maybe.
不管是什么  肯定让她产生过敏反应了
Whatever it was, she must have gone into anaphylaxis.
-我去  -是啊
- Damn. - Yeah.
血液检验应该能告诉我们
The blood sample should tell us
我们需要知道的一切
everything we need to know.
我会回实验室做测试
I'll run tests back at my lab.
在尖端实验室做更快
They can do it faster at S.T.A.R. Labs.
是  不过我是说  只是
Well, yeah, but, I mean, it's just...
只是什么
It's just what?
现在去那里感觉有些奇怪
It's kind of weird being there right now.
巴里  你知道咱们得在威尔斯前保持镇定
Barry, you know we have to play it cool with Wells.
如果让他发现我们怀疑他
If he finds out we suspect him--
我知道  我明白
I know. I get it.
我只是觉得我们应该告诉西斯科和凯特琳
I just think that we should tell Cisco and Caitlin.
他们可以帮助我们
They could help us.
越多人知道  就越有可能
The more people who know, the more chance
让威尔斯发现我们在调查他
Wells is gonna find out we're on to him.
我是说  万一他们有人说漏嘴了呢
I mean, what if one of them slips up?
或是慌了
Or panics?
-或者如果...  -什么
- Or what if... - What?
如果他们不是站在咱们这边的
What if they're not on our side?
不  肯定不会
No. Absolutely not.
他们绝对没有参与他的计划
They're not involved in whatever he's planning.
我是说  威尔斯是他们的老板  导师
I mean, Wells is their boss, their mentor.
他们和他在一起很久了
They've been with him for a long time.
我见过很多人因忠诚而做出错误决定
I've seen plenty of people make the wrong choice for loyalty.
我们没确定之前请千万别告诉他们
Please do not include them until we can be sure.
好吧
All right.
因蜂毒而死
Death by apitoxin.
蜜蜂的毒素
Honeybee venom.
蜜蜂   为什么要是蜜蜂
Bees. Why did it have to be bees?
跟你们说  我可不喜欢蜜蜂
Y'all, I don't do bees.
没人有时间对付蜜蜂
Ain't nobody got time for bees.
但是当蜜蜂蜇人时
But when a honeybee stings,
它们的蜂刺会从腹部被扯出
the stingers are literally torn from their abdomen,
然后它们就会死
and they die.
但是尸体上没有蜂刺
But there were no stingers in the body
车里也没有死蜜蜂
and no dead bees in the car.
一个蜜蜂释放蜂刺的时候
A honeybee can only deposit 0.1 milligrams of apitoxin
只能释放0.1毫克蜂毒
when it releases its stinger.
林赛·康
但是  我们在康女士体内
And yet, Ms. Kang was found
发现了足够杀死一群大象的毒素
with enough venom in her system to kill a herd of elephants.
显然那些蜜蜂不仅被超能力者控制了
It appears not only is a meta-human controlling these bees
还被增强了毒性
but also increasing their toxicity.
蜜蜂通过分泌信息素进行联络
Bees communicate by releasing pheromones.
也许这位超能者通过分泌物来控制它们
Maybe this meta's controlling them through secretion?
有人想要和我一起订套养蜂服吗
Anyone want to join me in getting a beekeeper suit?
我挺自信自己能跑过蜜蜂的
I'm pretty sure I can outrun a bee.
只是别跑进湖里了
Just don't run into a lake.
因为蜜蜂会等着你露出水面喘气
Bees will wait for you to come up for air
然后趁机叮你
and then they'll sting you.
探索频道看的  的确有很多事需要探索
Discovery Channel. Turns out there's a lot to discover.
费利西蒂  你怎么来了
Felicity, what are you doing here?
你们能出来一下吗
Can you guys come outside for a sec?
我们到底在等什么  斯莫克女士
What exactly are we waiting for, Ms. Smoak?
在上面
Up there.
那是只鸟吗
Is that a bird?
是架飞机
It's a plane.
是我男朋友
It's my boyfriend.
大家好  我是雷
Hi. I'm Ray.
他好像比你高很多
So he seems a little tall for you.
巴里·艾伦  你这是嫉妒他吗
Barry Allen, are you jealous?
嫉...  没有  我没有嫉妒
Je... no. No, I'm not jealous.
我只是  我只是觉得你们飞来之前
I just-- I really wish you would've called
应该打个电话
before flying in.
不对  他飞来的  我是开车来的
Oh no, He flied, I drove.
我不是在开玩笑
I'm serious, all right?
现在不是个好时候
Now is not the best time.
怎么了  发生什么了
Why? What's going on?
我的耳膜有点鼓  所以肯定有什么事
Well, my ears popped, so that's something.
你没把脖子折断就很走运了
You're lucky you didn't break your neck.
亿万富翁做超级英雄是什么感觉
What is it with billionaires being superheroes?
你...  起名字了吗
So have you... picked a name yet?
我比较喜欢原子侠
I'm kind of partial to The Atom.
你确定了吗  还是...
You married to that, or...?
你的原子战衣
Your A.T.O.M. Suit...
是个很了不起的技术成果  帕尔默先生
it's quite the technological achievement, Mr. Palmer.
让我很佩服
I'm impressed.
他从没佩服过别人
And he is never impressed.
谢谢你
Well, thank you,
但是我总是"挺不住"
but I can't quite seem to keep it up.
他指的是战衣
He means the suit.
-是的  我说的是战衣  -是的
- Yeah, I mean the suit. - Yeah.
我可以证明其它方面都很好
I can attest that everything else works just fine.
在那方面  我们没有什么需要
There's nothing we need to fix in...
改进的
that area.
是的  是的  做爱方面简直完美
No, no, no. The sex is great.
天哪  真是天生一对
God, there's two of them.
我从费利西蒂那得知你们一直在帮忙
I know from Felicity that you have been very helpful
帮巴里  以及帮忙做那件闪电侠战衣
with Barry and the Flash suit,
所以我希望你们也能看看我的...
and I was hoping to get another set of eyes on my...
-问题  -问题
- Problem. - Problem.
绿箭的朋友就是我们的朋友
Any friend of The Arrow's is a friend--
-当然可以  -各位
- Hell, yes. - Guys.
我们现在已经有很大的麻烦了
We kind of have a lot going on already.
现在有个超能力者凶手
There's the meta-human killer
他能控制一群蜜蜂
that can control a whole swarm of bees?
厉害啊
Cool.
我的意思是太糟糕了
I mean, awful.
我相信凯特琳和我
I'm sure Caitlin and I
能够为你提供足够的支持  巴里
will provide ample support, Barry.
而我这次很乐意不管你了
And I will be happy to sit this one out.
你
You...
雷  你留在这研究你的战衣
Ray, why don't you stay here and work on your suit
我和巴里去吉特喝点东西
while Barry and I run to Jitters for some java?
计划不错
Sounds like a plan.
-去喝咖啡吧  -可以
- Coffee? - Sure.
中城警局
-警探先生  -爱瑞丝
- Hey, Detective. - Iris.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
我在跟进我的报道
I am following up on my story
关于中城的犯罪事件
about crime in Central City.
如果没有的话
Or lack thereof.
是因为有人在跟闪电侠合作吗
Could someone be working with The Flash?
不是  当然不是
No. Of course not.
你昨晚抓到了一个露阴者
You caught a flasher,
几个开车逃跑的持枪抢劫犯
armed robbers in a getaway car,
还有两个珠宝大盗
and two jewelry thieves last night.
我就是那么厉害
I'm just that good.
你最近是怎么了
What is going on with you lately?
举止很奇怪  而且有些事都不跟我说
You've been acting really weird and withdrawn.
如果我不了解你的话
If I didn't know any better,
我还以为你是有事瞒着我
I'd think that you were hiding something from me.
爱瑞丝  我没有瞒着你什么
Iris, I'm-- I'm not hiding anything from you.
你还有去上过班吗
Do you ever go to work?
真有意思
Oh, you're funny.
我不能再对爱瑞丝隐瞒闪电侠的事了
Okay, I can't keep lying to Iris about The Flash.
必须瞒着
You have to.
这事已经开始影响我们的感情了
It's really starting to affect our relationship.
我们已经两个星期没上床了
We haven't had sex in two weeks.
当然你不想知道这种事
Which you didn't want to know about.
不让她知道就能保证她的安全
Keeping her in the dark keeps her safe.
我不同意
I don't agree.
我是她父亲
Well, I'm her father.
可我是她男朋友
And I'm her boyfriend.
什么时候我的话能比你的话重要
When does my vote outweigh yours?
等你成为她丈夫以后
When you become her husband.
我离开星城
You know I left Starling City
是为了躲开坏心情
to get away from the mood and brood,
不过好像它跟着我来了
but it looks like it followed me here.
我知道  对不起
I know. I'm sorry.
就像我之前说的
It's like I said before,
现在不是个好时候
now is not the best time.
巴里  我跟你经历过很多风风雨雨了
Barry, I have been through enough with you
所以我知道你心里藏着一些事
to know when you're holding something back.
是因为我把你的秘密告诉雷了吗
Is this because I told Ray your secret?
他非常可靠的  巴里
Because he is trustworthy, Barry.
他想帮助别人  和你一样
He wants to help people, just like you.
我知道  我不是担心这事
I know, that's not what I'm worried about.
只是
It's...
我真的不想让别人处于危险之中
I really don't want to put anyone else in danger.
处于什么危险
In danger of what?
巴里
Barry, hey.
艾迪
Eddie, hey.
-你还记得费利西蒂吧  -当然
- You remember Felicity. - Of course.
很高兴见到你
Great to see you.
我也是
Yeah.
你们怎么了
What is wrong with you?
中城所有人都不开心吗
Is everyone in Central City in a bad mood?
我还以为中城是充满乐趣的呢
I thought Central City was supposed to be the fun one.
只是
It's...
-不是  -费利西蒂知道的
- It's not... - Felicity knows.
所以只有爱瑞丝不知道
So everyone but Iris.
好像是的
It feels that way.
你是怎么做到对所有在乎的人说谎的
How do you lie to everyone you care about?
首先
For starters,
不要认为你在说谎
don't think of it as lying.
当作是为了保护她免受伤害
Think of it as protecting her from getting hurt...
不得已的说谎
with a fib.
但爱瑞丝能看出来我在瞒着她什么事
But Iris can tell I'm hiding something,
这让我们之间产生了隔阂
and it's putting this distance between us.
我有主意了
I have an idea.
不如我们一起吃个晚饭吧
Why don't we all go to dinner tonight?
喝点小酒吃点东西绝对能消除隔阂
A little wine and dine is sure to bridge the gap.
好吗  上次多好玩啊
Come on, we all had fun last time.
好吧  何乐不为呢
Sure. Why not?
巴里·艾伦  专业电灯泡
Barry Allen, fifth wheel.
福斯通科技
今天下午三点的会我是赶不上了
Well, I can't make my 3:00 meeting this afternoon.
还有  确认一下我晚上的订餐
also, confirm my dinner reservation for tonight.
上次他们说找不到预订信息
Last time, they couldn't find it,
这样的错误绝不许再犯  谢谢
and that was unacceptable. Thanks.
看到那边的那个大坏蛋了吗
You see that bad man over there?
告诉你的小姐妹们游戏时间到
Tell your sisters it's time.
你在腰带里嵌入了固体氧化物燃料电池
So you put solid oxide fuel cells into the belt?
是啊  这是唯一可以安装硬件的地方
Yeah, it's the only place to hide the hardware.
那就应该可以为战衣提供
Well, they should be generating enough energy
足够能量啊
to power the suit.
也可能是因为操作温度过高的问题
It could be the operating temperature.
你这样绝对
I mean, you're essentially--
系统过热了  我想也是
Overheating the system, yeah. I figured.
但如果我们用陶瓷
But if we insulate them
复合物隔离热量
with a ceramic compound...
也许就能提高操作效率
We may improve the operating efficiency.
你相当聪明  西斯科
You really are quite clever, Cisco.
有人说我是逆闪
Some would say I'm the reverse.
你相当聪明  西斯科
You're incredibly clever, Cisco.
这玩意儿怎么开啊
How do you turn this thing on?
西斯科  你没事吧
Cisco? You okay?
没事
Yeah.
最近没怎么睡好
I haven't been getting enough sleep...
西斯科  你得赶紧过来
Cisco, we need you up here.
杀人蜂又出现了
Killer bees are at it again.
联系巴里
Get a hold of Barry.
又出现了蜜蜂袭人事件  在福斯通科技
Another bee attack. Folston Tech.
我去联系乔
I'll see where Joe is.
-小心蜜蜂  -真的假的啊
- Bee careful. - For real?
这双关不太好  抱歉  请不要死
Bad pun. Sorry. Just don't die.
福斯通科技
我来晚了
I'm too late.
蜜蜂呢
Where are the bees?
不知道  没看到
I don't know. There's no sign of them.
找到了
Found them.
我怎么出去
How do I get out of here?
去东北方的那条岔道
Take the northeast crossway.
那是逃出大楼的最快路径
It's the quickest way out of the building.
伙计们  到处都是蜜蜂  我被包围了
Guys, they're everywhere. I'm surrounded.
巴里
Barry!
Barry.
他要心脏骤停了
He's going into cardiac arrest.
巴里  醒醒
Barry, stay with me.
西斯科·拉蒙
西斯科  摸不到巴里的脉搏了
Cisco! Barry doesn't have a pulse.
-离他远点  -什么  为什么
- Step away from him. - What? Why?
我们要给他做心脏起搏
We need to jumpstart his heart.
衣服里装有电击器
There's a defibrillator in the suit.
设定为360焦耳
Charge it to 360 joules.
电击倒数  三  二  一
Charging in three, two, one.
再来一次  400焦耳
Hit him again. 400 joules.
电击倒数  三  二  一
Charging in three, two, one.
巴里
Barry.
乔
Joe.
电击器也就这样了
That is it for the defibrillator.
完全烧焦了
It is completely fried.
你能活着就很幸运了  艾伦先生
You're lucky to be alive, Mr. Allen.
我说了让你不要死的
I was very specific that you not die.
她很在意这种事的
Yeah, that's a pretty big thing for her.
西斯科  怎么回事
Cisco, what happened out there?
我走的就是你指的路啊
I followed your directions exactly.
抱歉  是我指错路了
I'm sorry. I led you the wrong way.
我们记录的地形图
The schematics that we had,
没有及时更新
they... they weren't up to date.
What, they weren't up to date?
什么意思
What do you mean?
以前从来没出过这样的事啊
That's never happened before.
怎么  你以为是西斯科故意害你吗
What, you think Cisco was trying to get you killed?
没有  他怎么会这么做
No. Why would he do that?
没道理啊
That doesn't make any sense.
我知道  所以才这么开个玩笑啊
I know. That's why I was joking.
巴里  我们的工作就是保护你
Barry, it's our job to protect you,
今天是我们的失误
and today, we failed,
这是个很好的提醒
but that'll just serve as a warning
让我们以后能更加警觉
for all of us to be more vigilant in the future.
好消息  蜂毒已经完全排除了
Good news -- the apitoxin is out of your body.
你的指标已经正常了
Your levels are back to normal.
太好了
Terrific.
雷  费利西蒂  晚餐要迟到了
Ray, Felicity. We're gonna be late for dinner.
你真觉得可以去吗  巴里
Are you sure that's wise, Barry?
你差点死掉啊
You just died.
要不今晚别出去吃了
Maybe you should order in tonight.
是啊  我们可以取消的
Yeah, we could totally cancel.
我没事  还活着  而且饿了
I'm fine. Alive. Hungry.
好吗  走吧
All right? Let's go.
他有点怪
That was weird.
就是啊  为什么不邀请我们一起去
Yeah. Why didn't we get invited to dinner?
谢谢
Thank you.
你们好啊
Hey, guys.
爱瑞丝  瞧瞧你多美啊
Wow, Iris. Check you out.
费利西蒂
Hi, Felicity.
你好
Hello.
各位  这是雷·帕尔默
Guys, this is Ray Palmer.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
Lovely to meet you.
-很高兴见到你  -巴里
- Nice to meet you. - Barry.
欢迎光临马西莫酒店
Bienvenue chez Massimo Restaurant.
帕尔默先生  您的桌子已经备好
Mr. Palmer, your table is ready.
太好了  走吧
Great. Shall we?
好的
Yes.
他是怎么在这里订到位子的
Hey, how did he get a reservation here?
我们订了几个月都没订上
We've been trying for months.
我不知道
I don't know.
你们的位置在这里  先生
Here's your table, sir.
我想环境安静一点会比较好
I thought it'd be nice if it was quiet,
所以就包下了整个餐厅
so I bought out the entire restaurant.
太过了吗
Too much?
有一点  宝贝
Just a tad, sweetie.
乔
Joe.
西斯科
Oh, Cisco.
正好省得我去尖端科研实验室找你了
You just saved me a trip to S.T.A.R. Labs.
我找到一些第二个死者的信息
I got some info on our second victim.
他叫比尔·卡莱尔
Name's Bill Carlisle.
福斯通科技最近聘请他
He was recently hired at Folston Tech
中城警局
加入他们的机器人技术部门
to beef up their Robotics Division.
机器人技术
Robotics?
跟第一个死者一样
That's just like the first victim.
真奇怪
That is weird.
你过来不是为了取资料的
That's not why you stopped by.
是的  我来是想跟你谈谈巴里
No, I wanted to talk to you about Barry.
好的
Okay.
他最近是不是有什么事
Is there something going on with him?
他没有告诉我们的事
Something he's not telling us?
你指什么
What do you mean?
他最近有点不太像他了
He hasn't really been himself lately.
我没听说有什么事啊
Not that I'm aware of.
好像他在为什么事而烦心
It's like something is just really bothering him.
我想他一门心思
Well, I think he's got his mind trained on
想着抓坏人吧  西斯科
catching the bad guys, Cisco.
他可能还在担心
And he's probably worried about
逆闪电会再次出现在他面前
when The Reverse-Flash is gonna show his face again.
我可与闪电侠不同
Oh, I'm not like The Flash at all.
可以说我们是相反的
Some would say I'm the reverse.
你没事吧
You okay?
是的  没事  我很好
Yeah. Yeah, no, I'm fine.
只是  我的头特别疼
It's just--I've got this crazy headache.
谢谢你的文件还有谈话
Thank you for the file and the talk.
你们俩是怎么认识的
So how did you two meet?
工作
Work.
其实
Well, actually,
我买下了费利西蒂所在的公司
I bought the company where Felicity was employed,
所以她被迫加入到我的帕尔默科技来
and so she was forced to join me at Palmer Tech.
没有他说得那么可怕
It's not as creepy as it sounds.
这么说你们俩一起工作是吗
So you two work closely together?
有趣
Interesting.
我想你们俩一定共同分享彼此的想法
I guess you guys share all of your thoughts
感受还有...
and feelings and...
是的  我什么都跟费利西蒂分享
Yeah... I share everything with Felicity.
你们俩沟通得这么好真让人羡慕
It's nice that you guys have that level of communication.
不  也不是所有事都分享的
Oh, well, no, not every-everything.
有些事还是不要说得好
I mean, sometimes it's good to just shut up.
我明白了
I get that.
有些事还是不要说出来为好
Some things are better left unspoken.
是吗
Really?
我觉得不尽然吧
I-I don't find that to be true.
谢天谢地  吃的来了
Oh, thank God. It's the food.
吃的来了
Food's here.
菜单上的第一道菜是
Our first course on the tasting menu
鹌鹑蛋菜肉馅煎蛋饼
is a quail egg frittata.
愿你们胃口好
Bon appetit.
巴里
Barry.
我得承认
I got to admit,
我嫉妒你可以在尖端科研实验室待那么久
I envy you spending so much time at S.T.A.R. Labs.
哈里森·威尔斯是我心目中的英雄
Harrison Wells is, like, a personal hero of mine.
只是跟他同处一室
I mean, it's amazing just to actually
也会让人觉得很神奇
be in the same room with him.
我马上就回来  失陪一下
I'll be right back. Just excuse me.
好的
Okay.
我...
Well, I, um...
去趟卫生间
have to pee.
从我和雷来到中城以后
Okay, you've been acting super strange
你就一直表现得如此怪异
ever since Ray and I got to Central City.
你到底是怎么了
What is going on with you?
别跟我说现在情况不好
And don't say it's a bad time.
奥利弗可能会加入刺客联盟
Oliver might be joining the League of Assassins,
劳蕾尔是黑金丝雀
Laurel's the Black Canary,
而西娅和马尔科姆一起训练
and Thea's training with Malcolm,
所以我知道什么叫情况不好
so I know about bad times.
好吧
Okay.
乔和我发现威尔斯并不是他表面的样子
Joe and I found out that Wells isn't who he says he is.
他...
He...
他是杀害我母亲的那个人
He is the man that killed my mother.
天呐  可他一直在帮助你
Oh, my God. But he's been helping you.
帮我变快  变强  我知道
Get faster, stronger. I know.
-为什么  -我不知道
- Why? - I don't know.
我什么都不知道了
I don't know anything anymore,
尤其不知道该相信谁  不该相信谁
especially who I can and can't trust.
你认为西斯科和凯特琳在帮助他吗
So you think Cisco and Caitlin are helping him?
那不可能
That's impossible.
是吗
Is it?
是的  他们今天还试图要救你的命  巴里
Yes. They were trying to save you today, Barry.
他们的确救了你的命
They did save you.
威尔斯也救过我的命
Wells has also saved me.
很多次
Many times.
我以为威尔斯是个大好人
I thought that Wells was a great man,
结果证明我看错他了
and I was so wrong about him.
万一其它事我也看错了怎么办
What if I'm wrong about everything else too?
二位
Hey, guys.
外面的情形有点紧张了
Uh, things are getting a little intense in here.
咱们就不能好好度过一个晚上吗
Please can't we just have a nice evening?
原来是因为我的缘故
Okay, so it's my fault
才让我们不能好好度过一个晚上吗
that we're not having a nice evening?
我是你的女朋友  跟你住在一起
I am your girlfriend. Who you live with.
我不应该求你让你跟我说话的
I shouldn't have to beg you to talk to me.
如果可以对你说的话  我会的  相信我
If I could talk to you about this, I would, believe me.
但我不能说
But I can't.
好吧  我一点也不饿了
You know what? I am not hungry anymore.
-爱瑞丝  -不如这样
- Iris. - You know what?
等你准备好跟我一起
When you are ready to act like
装得好像深爱彼此的样子时
we are two people who love each other,
再给我打电话
call me.
我会去我爸爸那住
I'll be at my dad's.
谢谢你的晚餐  我得走了
Thank you for dinner. I've got to go.
尖端科研实验室有紧急情况
Uh, emergency at S.T.A.R. Labs.
快去
Go.
抱歉
Sorry.
好吧  只剩下17道菜没上了
Well, only 17 more courses to go.
封锁泄漏   监测到外来物体
Containment breach. Foreign object detected.
我打到它了吗
Did I get it?
我觉得好像打到它了
I think I got it.
他在哪儿啊
Where is he?
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们来看看是什么让这蜜蜂这么毒
Let's see what makes this bee so poisonous.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
这蜜蜂长得可真奇怪啊
That is one odd-looking bee.
那是因为它根本不是蜜蜂
That's 'cause it isn't a bee at all.
这是个机器蜂
It's a robot.
不可能
No way.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
这机器蜂有360度的视觉系统
This bot's got a 360-degree vision system.
我是说  咱们面对的是多个微型摄像头
I mean, we're talking multiple micro-cameras
同时从各个角度拍摄
all coming from various angles at the same time.
这意味着
Which means...
它可以同时看到整个房间
It can see all around the room at once.
这真是
That is...
不可思议
Amazing.
明明是讨厌
Disturbing.
它用的也是远超于市面水平的新一代硬件
It's also next-gen hardware that'nowhere near the market.
所以我们对付的不是超能力者
So we're not dealing with a meta-human?
只是一个疯子科学家
It's just a mad scientist.
西斯科  你说第二个受害者
Cisco, you said the second victim,
比尔·卡莱尔是个机器人工程师
Bill Carlisle, was a robotics engineer.
我们把他和林赛·康之前的雇主
Let's cross-reference his previous employers
交叉搜索一下吧
with those of Lindsay Kang.
让我来吧
Allow me.
老娘我太久没摸键盘了
Mama's been away from a keyboard for far too long.
好吧
Okay.
水星实验室
他们都在水星实验室工作过
They both worked at Mercury Labs.
我们来给乔打个电话
Let's call Joe.
我觉得是时候去探望一位老朋友了
I think it's time we paid a visit to an old friend.
一年两次啊  哈里森
Twice in one year, Harrison.
你真是要竞争年度最佳复出科学家啊
You really are vying for comeback scientist of the year.
总是高兴见到你  克里斯提娜
Always a pleasure, Christina.
我怎么有幸让您大驾光临
To what do I owe this visit?
你是终于找到了我的超光速粒子原型机
Did you finally find my tachyon prototype,
还是来勒索我再给你一个
or are you here to blackmail me for another one?
你有第二个吗
Do you have another one?
我们过来是想问你一点事
We came here for information.
比尔·卡莱尔和林赛·康
Bill Carlisle and Lindsay Kang.
前任雇员最近被谋杀了
Former employees who were recently murdered.
天呐  我还不知道这事
My God. I wasn't aware.
被机器蜂叮死的
Stung to death by robotic bees.
你要找的人是布里·拉万
You're looking for Brie Larvan.
布里·拉万
Brie Larvan?
她是个很聪明的机器人专家
A quite brilliant roboticist who once developed
曾经开发出农用的微型机器蜜蜂
miniature mechanical bees for agricultural use.
康和卡莱尔警告过我
Kang and Carlisle warned me
布里把蜜蜂武器化  以作为军用
that Brie was weaponizing the bees for military use,
所以我解雇了她
so I terminated her.
看上去你也在
Well, it seems that you would
她的刺杀名单上呢  博士
be on her hit list too, Doctor.
你得让我们保护你的安全
You've got to let us keep you safe.
我太了解
I'm all too familiar
你在保护东西方面的无能了  哈里森
with your inability to protect things, Harrison.
我能照顾好自己
I can take care of myself.
再见  先生们
Good day, gentlemen.
谢谢
Thank you.
所以我们找到蜂后了
Okay, so we found our queen bee.
布里·拉万  她是个机器人专家
Brie Larvan. She's a roboticist.
乔在跟进一条关于她现在住址的线索
Joe is running a trace on her current location,
但目前毫无头绪
but so far nothing.
好的
Good.
雷在哪儿
Where is Ray?
他在和西斯科弄他的战衣
Oh, he's working on his suit with Cisco.
我喜欢雷
I like Ray.
他看上去像个好人
He seems like he's a really good guy.
他是一个好男人
He is a good guy.
像西斯科一样
Just like Cisco.
还有凯特琳  好女人
And Caitlin. Girl.
这就是你叫我过来的原因吗
Is that why you called me here?
我知道你身处两难境地
I know that you're in a tricky situation,
但这时候你正需要朋友帮你撑腰
but that's when you need your friends to have your back.
如果你一味拒绝  他们怎么帮你
And how can they if you won't let them?
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
如果乔是对的
What if Joe is right,
我告诉他们之后  坏了事怎么办
and I tell them, and it backfires?
威尔斯不只是他们的上司  费利西蒂
Wells isn't just their boss, Felicity.
他是他们的导师  他们的英雄
He is their mentor, their hero.
我的英雄
My hero.
听着  这...
Look, it's...
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
当我刚认识奥利弗的时候
When I first met Oliver,
在我知道他是绿箭侠之前
before I knew he was The Arrow,
他会  他会让我帮忙做些很奇怪的事
he would--he would ask me to do weird things for him,
比如解密满是弹孔的电脑里的文件
like decrypt a bullet-ridden computer,
或者黑进什么公司
or hack some company.
而当我问他为什么的时候
And when I would ask him why,
他会编出一堆奇葩的理由
he would come up these ridiculous excuses.
我一直都知道他在说谎
And I always knew he was lying,
但我还是会帮他
but I would help him anyway.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为我知道奥利弗是个心地善良的好人
Because I knew Oliver was a good person with a good heart.
而西斯科和凯特琳
And Cisco and Caitlin?
他们也一样
They're no different.
所以你今晚真的要留下过夜吗
So you're really staying here tonight?
今晚  明晚
Tonight. Tomorrow night.
大后天晚上
The night after that.
你觉得艾迪在背着我偷腥吗
Do you think that Eddie is cheating on me?
不  艾迪不是那种人
No. Eddie's not that kind of guy.
好吧  那我真不知道
Well, then I don't know what else
那他还能瞒我什么
he could be hiding from me.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
你还记得我们小时候
Remember when we were kids,
乔下班回家
and Joe would come home from work
脸上空洞的表情
with that blank expression on his face?
记得
Yeah.
那种魂不守舍的恍惚神情
The "Earth to Joe" Look.
我怎么忘得了
How could I forget?
我一直不明白那表情的含义
I never understood that look
直到我开始在中城警局上班
until I started workg for the CCPD.
去到犯罪现场  看到有人被谋杀
Showing up at crime scenes and seeing someone murdered--
这工作有时挺难做的
it can be ugly work.
而我很幸运
And I'm lucky.
我可以躲在科学的后面
I get to hide behind the science of it
只待在实验室里就可以
and just stay in my lab,
但艾迪
but Eddie,
他每天都跑在外面  置身黑暗之中
he's out there every day in the darkness.
我只是在想  也许
I just--I think that maybe
如果他不想跟你说他工作上的事
if he doesn't want to talk to you about his work,
很可能是因为他想让你处在光明中
it's probably because he wants to keep you in the light.
怎么了
What?
我只是觉得很惊讶
I'm just surprised.
你这么坦诚的帮我
You going out of your way like this
理解艾迪的立场
to help me see Eddie's point of view.
我的意思是
I mean...
艾迪可以让你开心
Eddie makes you happy.
我想要的就是你开心  爱瑞丝
All I ever want is for you to be happy, Iris.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
看成年男人玩玩具真是太有趣了
It is so fun to watch grown men play with their toys.
你真幸运
You're so lucky.
雷人好又机智还很帅
Ray is so nice and smart and hot.
就像在跟巴里恋爱
Yeah, it's kind of like I'm dating Barry
不过是用奥利弗的身体
but in Oliver's body.
你绝不能跟别人提起这话
A sentence you will never repeat to anyone.
我肯定会帮你保密的
Your secret's safe with me.
它肯定被重新激活了
It must have re-activated.
如果它是被远程控制的
And if it's being controlled wirelessly...
我就能追踪到信号源并且找出
I can trace its signal and figure out
它们要去哪
where it's trying to go.
水星实验室
-不  -天哪
- Oh, no. - Oh, boy.
怎么了
What?
蜂群飞向水星实验室了
The swarm is headed for Mercury Labs.
布里·拉万要去袭击蒂娜
Brie Larvan's going after Tina.
你好啊  麦吉博士
Hello, Dr. McGee.
是你打开窗户  还是我自己钻进去
You gonna open the window, or should I buzz myself in?
我们怎么阻止它们
How do we stop them?
她肯定是在某个地方
She's got to be remotely piloting
远程部署这些蜜蜂
those bees from somewhere.
我们得阻止这个戴眼镜的暴眼女
We need to stop this bug-eyed glasses woman.
还有她的迷你手下
And her mini bandits.
暴眼大盗
Bug-Eyed Bandit.
找到她了  她在一所废弃的温室里
Got her. She's in an abandoned greenhouse.
巴里  你去搞定布里
Barry, you have to take out Brie.
那是阻止这些微型无人机的唯一办法
It's the only way to stop these nano drones.
那麦吉博士呢
What about Dr. McGee?
你衣服里的电击器坏了
The defibrillator in your suit is broken.
你不能冒险去水星实验室
You cannot risk going near Mercury Labs.
蜜蜂不能穿透我的战衣
Bees can't penetrate my suit.
我去
I'll go.
我们还没检测过新动力系统
We haven't tested out the new power system yet.
我们现在检测
We'll do it now.
-我跟着去  -我开车
- I'm following you. - I'm driving.
我要吻你
And I'm kissing you.
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells...
帕尔默会去保护蒂娜的  去吧
Mr. Palmer will protect Tina. Go.
你炒了我  毁掉了我多年的研究
You fired me, destroyed years of my research.
你夺走了我的一切
You took everything from me.
你所做的是错的
What you were doing was wrong.
你想伤害大家  而不是帮助大家
You wanted to harm people, not help them.
我做了我必须做的
I did what I had to do.
你是说毁掉我的人生吗
You mean ruin my life?
好
Sure.
现在我要做我必须做的
Now I'm doing what I have to do.
水星
找到她了
Found her.
费利西蒂  你能干扰它们的频率吗
Felicity, can you jam their frequency?
我已经试了  不过我应该可以把它们
I already tried, but I might be able to redirect them
引向一个新目标
onto a new target.
雷  准备好迎接来袭
Ray, get ready for incoming.
我们有解决的技术
We have the technology.
水星实验室
都结束了  布里
It's over, Brie.
我知道你想杀麦吉博士
I know you're trying to kill Dr. McGee.
你认为她背叛了你
You think that she betrayed you.
我能想象到这种感受
I can imagine how that feels.
你认为你能理解被背叛的刺痛吗
You think you understand the sting of betrayal?
我来给你展示一下被刺是什么感觉
I'll show you what it means to be stung.
巴里
Barry.
巴里  我黑入了蜜蜂的频率系统
Barry, I hacked into the bees' frequency.
我在控制它们
I'm controlling them.
我是这个蜂群的女王
I'm the queen of this hive.
她真厉害
Oh, she's good.
她就像我的劲敌
She's like my nemesis.
我以前从没遇到过劲敌
I've never had a nemesis before.
感觉还不错
I kind of like it.
好了  西斯科  现在怎么做
Okay, Cisco. Now what?
雷  去大海
Ray, get to the ocean.
如果机器跟你去到水里
If the bots follow you into the water,
他们的电子设备就会短路
their electronics will fry.
明白了
Got it.
等等  但我的衣服也会啊
Wait. But so will my suit.
西斯科  我短路了
Cisco, I'm fried.
我失去推动控制了
I'm losing propulsion control.
你看到货车了吗
Can you see the van?
看到了
Yeah.
我们接住你
We'll catch you.
-你会吗  -我们会吗
- You will? - We will?
我们会接住的
We will.
好吧
All right.
稳住
Keep it steady.
原子侠活下来了
The Atom lives.
下次装个更软点的手套  好吗
Let's work on some softer gloves for next time, okay?
抱歉
Sorry.
你想开战吗
Oh, you want to bring it?
已经开始了
It's been brought.
太无礼了
Rude.
费利西蒂  现在
Felicity, right now
是该做点什么了
would be a good time to do something.
离巴里·艾伦远点
Stay away from Barry Allen.
-费利西蒂  -搞定了
- Felicity! - Got it.
赢了  扔掉麦克风
Boom. Drop the mic.
当然只是比喻而已
It's metaphorical, of course,
因为我并没有真正的麦克风
because I don't have a real mic.
布里已经被控制了
Brie's restrained.
打电话给中城警局
Call CCPD.
你们还真是个团队啊
Some kind of team you have here.
有朋友跟你在一起总是有用的
Helps to have friends in your corner.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
西斯科
Cisco!
快起来  拜托
Come on. Please.
醒醒
Wake up.
西斯科被蜜蜂蛰到  就要休克了
Cisco's been stung. He's going into shock.
我马上赶过去
I'm on my way.
拜托  坚持住
Come on, stay with me.
等等  大家退后
Hold on. Back up.
我要试试其它的办法
I'm gonna try something.
西斯科
Cisco.
不是我对蜜蜂的恐惧消失了  就是更严重了
Either my fear of bees is over or it just got a lot worse.
感谢上帝  你没事了
Thank God you're okay.
头一回有人为我挺身而出被蜜蜂蜇
I've never had anybody take a bee for me.
-谢谢你  -不客气  哥们
- Thank you. - You're welcome, bro.
西斯科  你真是个英雄
Cisco, you're a hero, man.
-麦吉博士  -我能进来吗
- Dr. McGee. - May I come in?
当然能  我有什么能帮你的吗
Yeah, of course. What can I do for you?
我想要向你道歉
I wanted to apologize.
在你向我警告布里时  我应该听你说
I should have listened to you when you warned me about Brie.
也许下次我会接受中城警署的保护
Perhaps next time I will take the CCPD's offer of protection.
在我们丢失你的超光速粒子原型之后
After we lost your tachyon prototype,
我能理解你为什么不愿相信我们
I can understand why you were hesitant to trust us.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我能问你件事吗
Can I ask you something?
我注意到你和威尔斯博士之间
I couldn't help but notice some tension
有些隔阂
between you and Dr. Wells.
那些都是过去的事了
That's all in the past.
你介意我问问你们之间发生了什么事吗
Do you mind if I ask what happened between you two?
我一直在问自己同样的问题
I ask myself that same question all the time.
十五年前  我和哈里森交情深厚
15 years ago, Harrison and I were thick as thieves.
我们都是星城里前途无量的年轻科学家
We were promising young scientists in Starling City.
他以前是个很善良的人
He was such a kind man.
泰丝去世后  一切都变了
Then everything changed after Tess died.
他们当时要结婚了吗
They were gonna get married?
我明白悲伤对人的影响有多大
I understand how grief can affect someone,
但事情好像不止是这样
but this was more than that.
就像是在那天之后
It was like, after that day,
哈里森·威尔斯博士完全变成了另外一个人
Harrison Wells became a completely different person.
日安
Good day.
再见
Bye.
博士
Doctor.
西斯科怎么样了
How's Cisco?
很幸运还活着
Happy to be alive.
但是雷要离开了  我很难过
And sad that Ray is leaving.
他所做的事真的很勇敢  冒着生命危险
It was a really brave thing he did, risking his life.
非常无私
Selfless.
没错  绝对没错
Yeah. It definitely was.
又一次中城的刺激冒险结束了
And another end to another exciting adventure in Central City.
太好了  谢谢
Yes, thank you.
雷  非常感谢你帮了这么多忙
Ray, thank you for all your help.
我希望你能找出你战衣所存在的问题
And I hope you figure out the problem with your suit.
其实我已经找到问题了
I already have, actually.
一直以来  我在电源方面
All this time, I've been looking at
一直找错了方向
the power source the wrong way.
我一直在想我们需要更大的电源
I kept thinking we needed to go bigger.
但是解决办法却和平常一样
But the solution, as always,
只是变得更小就行了
is simply to go smaller.
好极了
Great.
你没事吧
You okay?
我会没事的
I'm gonna be.
谢谢你的建议
Thank you for your advice.
我甚至都不会收你钱
I won't even charge you the 5 cents.
再见  费利西蒂
Bye, Felicity.
再见  巴里
Bye, Barry.
怎么了
What's up?
我
I...
昨晚我和巴里聊过了
I spoke to Barry last night.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
他试着帮助我去理解
He was trying to help me understand
你为什么最近一直心不在焉
why you've been so off lately,
为什么你可能与我沟通有困难
why you might be having trouble connecting with me.
真的吗
Really?
他说了什么
What did he say?
他解释得很不错
It was a good explanation.
很合理
Valid.
但事实是  那都不重要了
But the truth is, it doesn't matter,
因为当你爱着一个人时
because when you love someone,
你就会告诉他们一切
you tell them everything.
所以如果你爱我  艾迪
So if you love me, Eddie,
就告诉我你到底有什么事  不然
you'll tell me what is going on with you, or...
不然怎样
Or what?
你知道的
You know what.
好吧  好吧  谁想要去
All right, all right, who's ready for some...
唱卡拉OK
karaoke.
我们不是真要去唱卡拉OK吧
We are not going to karaoke, are we?
不是
No.
这是我们手上所有关于我妈妈的谋杀案
This is everything we know about my mother's murder
和逆闪电的资料
and The Reverse-Flash.
长期以来  我一直在收集和他有关的信息
I've been gathering information on him for a long time.
而这是所有和威尔斯博士有关的资料
And this is everything we know about Dr. Wells.
我不明白
I don't understand.
威尔斯博士和逆闪电之间
What do Dr. Wells and The Reverse-Flash
有什么关系呢
have to do with each other?
他们是同一个人
They're the same person.
这是不可能的
That's impossible.
听着  凯特琳
Look, Caitlin,
我也花了很长时间才相信这件事
it took me a long time to believe it too,
但就是他
but it's him.
威尔斯博士是一个极速者
Dr. Wells is a speedster?
他双腿瘫痪了
He's paralyzed.
是吗
Is he, though?
况且他为什么要杀巴里的妈妈呢
And why would he kill Barry's mother?
这完全说不通啊
It doesn't make any sense.
西斯科  说话啊
Cisco. Say something.
我一直在做同一个梦
I've been having these dreams.
通常都在晚上  但有时白天也会有
Mostly at night, but sometimes during the day.
但是感觉真的不像是在做梦
But they don't really feel like dreams.
感觉  感觉很真实
They... they feel real.
梦里都发生了什么事
What happens in the dream?
威尔斯博士就是逆闪电
Dr. Wells is The Reverse-Flash.
而且
And...
他还杀了我
he kills me.